_
There are times when we make history,
and there are times
when history makes us.
This is a crucial moment for our nation,
and America's colors burn brightest
colors: 성조기
when we meet challenges head on.
For far too long,
the wealthiest 1% have
seen their fortunes only grow
while the rest of
the nation lies in worry.
That needs to change.
The question is, how do we pay for it?
But the question is,
how do we pay for it?
It's not even in the
vicinity of what we agreed on.
vicinity:근처,비슷한것
No! This is not a quid pro quo.
quid pro quo : 대가, 보상 (Latin, "what for what")
This is "You do what I say when I say it
or you suffer the consequences."
Uh, it's beyond bedti...
Penny, y-you need to
go to sleep right now.
Let me talk to her.
No, you can't talk to Dad.
Let me talk to her. Come on.
And not just here at home...
Hello?
Hi, Daddy.
Who is this?
It's Penny.
Penny who?
Penny Kirkman, your daughter.
No, that's not possible.
My daughter's asleep, and I know that
because I kissed her good
night almost two hours ago.
When are you and Mommy coming home?
It doesn't matter. You're gonna
be asleep by then, right?
Right?
She can't keep pulling this.
I've got an idea.
What if you go to bed right now
and I let you stay up an
extra hour tomorrow night
so we can hang out?
- Sound like a deal?
- Deal.
That's my girl.
Give me a kiss.
Good night, Daddy.
Good night, little pea.
See? All good.
Not all good.
What do you mean, not all good?
Tom, you can't do that.
You can't make promises that
you won't be able to keep.
We're in Washington.
They're the only promises
we're allowed to make.
You know, you need to learn
how to set some limits with her.
Because if not, she is
gonna walk all over you.
walk all over : 말을 안듣다
I know.
You're right.
...values that we hold
dear, that represent who we are...
hold dear : 가치있게 여기다
Here come the greatest hits.
greatest hits : best of album
...to ensure you that
the same American dream
shared by our fathers, our mothers,
and their fathers and...
That's weird.
이상하네
- What is it?
- It won't come back on.
See if you can get it to work.
Okay.
Yeah.
No, I know. Ours just went black, too.
Tom!
- Oh, my God!
- I'll get back to you.
Mr. Secretary, you
need to put the phone down.
Secretary:장관
- Mike, what the hell is going on?
- I said put the phone down.
- Okay, okay.
- Ma'am, your phone.
We've lost contact with the Capitol.
We're sheltering in place
until we know more.
I need your government-issued BlackBerry.
What?
Do you have any other devices on you?
- Uh...
- Please, check your bag, ma'am.
But I... But I... I need...
We are getting reports
of some kind of explosion in
or around the Capitol building.
We are still...
Mr. Secretary, get
away from the window, now!
Oh, my God.
Oh.
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --
_
I thought you said you were
gonna get some sleep.
I'm okay.
National Sleep Foundation
recommends seven hours
to function as a normal human being.
A working mother only needs four.
Uh, correction... Only gets four.
Hey.
No. No.
- I'm not doing anything.
- Tom, I have...
No. Stop it. I have work to do.
So do I, and it's a two-person job.
Come on. You've always said
you're always on my side.
Mm. Yes.
That's all I want.
- Mom!
- No, no, no, no.
Go away!
Dad! Get out here!
I'm hungry! I want some breakfast!
Leave us alone! You are not loved!
Please!
- No.
- Are you kidding?
Okay. You're gonna get what you deserve.
- I'm making breakfast.
- No. No, no, no.
- Pancakes for everyone!
- Please, no!
Let me go, woman!
Oh, God.
Okay, little pea. How
do you like your eggs?
Scrambled or scrambled?
Um, scrambled, please.
Excellent.
Scrambled eggs coming up
for the beautiful girl
sitting at the counter.
And there we go.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Leo. Perfect timing. What do you want?
Uh...
He's making breakfast?
Unfortunately.
Hey, I'm slaving over here.
I'll just get some toast.
Toast, toast.
That's made with bread, right?
Come on. You used to
always laugh at my jokes.
I used to be nine.
Ah, the good ol' days.
Hey, I need you to watch
your sister tonight, okay?
Uh, no. I can't do it. I'm busy.
I know... Watching your sister.
Come on. It's a big night for me.
I've got the State of the Union.
State of the Union: 연두교서.
Well, it is for me, too.
I told Caleb I'd help
him out with something.
- With what?
- It doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter
because I won't like it
or doesn't matter 'cause
I won't understand?
Both.
Okay, now I really want to know.
He's laying down a new dubstep track,
and I need to write a program for him.
I understood "him."
On a scale of 1 to 10,
how much do I embarrass you?
- 11.
- Excellent.
Hey, you finish your English paper yet?
- Uh, in theory.
- Finish it.
You can take them, right? I
have to be at court by 9:00.
Yeah, I got them.
Bye, peanut.
Bye, Mommy.
Make us proud.
...immigration reform, but
the sad truth of the matter
is that Richmond can promise
all he wants tonight...
This Congress isn't gonna
lift a finger to help him.
Well, this can't be good
if it won't even wait
till I get to the office.
How about the end of days?
I just spoke to Gillings
at Cabinet Affairs.
He slipped me a final copy
of Richmond's address
and none, not a single one of
our talking points are included.
You're kidding me.
Not even housing reform?
All of it, everything you and I have
worked our asses
off on for months, gone.
Okay, okay.
Just get me a meeting with
Langdon as soon as possible.
Already done. We're going there now.
It's time to war up.
Easy, Hannibal.
We should also talk about
leaking your plan to Politico
- if this doesn't work.
- No, that'll backfire.
Maybe, but it'll be out there.
Tonight is about what's in
the State of the Union,
not what's not.
We can't just let the White
House take an eraser
to our entire domestic agenda.
You're the Secretary of Housing
and Urban Development.
It's the President's
domestic agenda, Em.
It's your domestic agenda,
Mr. Secretary.
Okay, and I'll make my argument for it.
Look, don't get me wrong.
I'm as mad as hell.
But at the end of the day,
I'm not the President
of the United States.
We should remember that.
All right. Then let's
go see the Chief of Staff.
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you, sir.
We need to tell the
American people how we're doing,
and we need to get specific.
Could one of you please
find me something heavy
to hit Mr. Wright with? Thank you.
I'm telling you. We need to take
a look at the AB-33 section,
okay? The message is muddled.
I wrote it, and I
don't even know what it says.
That is the mark of a
successful political speech.
Well done. Now, go forth.
- Mr. Secretary, welcome. Please.
- Charlie.
I'm sure you remember Aaron
Shore, my Deputy Chief of Staff.
- Aaron, good to see you.
- Mr. Secretary.
I'm gonna hazard a guess
and say you're not here
to discuss which color tie the
President is wearing tonight.
That is his call...
if he'll put back in the
Secretary's housing initiatives.
These are programs that can help
millions of low-income families.
No one's debating its value here, Emily.
Charlie, there's not a single mention
of any of my programs
in the speech tonight?
- Not a one?
- I know. I'm sorry, Mr. Secretary,
but that's how it's
gonna be. The speech is locked.
Does the President value the
Secretary's opinion, Charlie?
Because right now, it's hard to tell.
Em.
Give us a moment.
I'll meet you outside.
What's going on, Charlie?
Well, Tom, we were gonna wait till after
the State of the Union to tell you this,
but the President's looking
to make a change.
He would like to
offer you an ambassadorship
to the International
Civil Aviation Organization.
Are you serious?
Was the Chairman of the
International House of Pancakes unavailable?
Tom...
Wow.
This is really not
how I saw today going.
Uh...
The Civil Aviation Committee...
- Organization.
Is that even a real thing, Charlie?
Of course it's a thing.
It's in Montreal. It's under the U.N.
Look, it affords you
the rank of ambassador
with all the trimmings
that go along with it.
Come on, Charlie. We've
done some good work here.
And we've got lots left to do, I mean...
I have supported this president
above and beyond for his entire term.
Well, now it's about the second term.
And I serve at the pleasure
of the President.
So do you, Tom.
Don't they realize what a
huge asset you are for them?
Langdon actually tried to
pass it off as a promotion.
Uh, you can't take this lying down.
- How else do you want me to take it?
- Fight.
Look, he appointed you,
but he can't fire you.
You need to hold your ground.
What do you want me to do?
Go to war with the President
of the United States?
The White House never respected you.
That's the real problem.
No, Alex. The real problem is
I didn't play
Richmond's game all the time.
Oh, Tom, come on!
It's called politics.
- And maybe if you did...
- What?
I wouldn't be out of a job?
Maybe, but then I'd be
just like one of those guys,
and when I got into this, we had a deal.
I wasn't gonna be one of those guys.
- I don't want to be...
- Tom, it's taken three years.
And we finally settled into Washington.
I love my job.
Penny loves her school.
Even Leo's making friends.
We can't do this to our family.
I know.
You're right.
Come here. Come here.
Hey.
I love you.
We'll make this work.
I'll commute.
What?
So, you've made up your mind?
You're stepping down?
I told them I'd give them
my decision tomorrow.
Wow.
Alex.
Great.
Yeah?
What's a designated survivor?
Mr. Secretary, we need to leave now.
- Tom!
- Did you see that?
...motorcade to smoke out any ambush.
White House is secure. Let's go.
Mike, please, just
tell us what you know.
Capitol's been attacked.
There's still no word on
the President or his detail.
This is Ritter.
Oh, God. Don't tell me that.
What is it?
It's confirmed.
Eagle is gone.
- Congress, the Cabinet.
- Oh, oh, my God.
None of them made it.
Yes, sir.
I'll let him know.
Mr. Secretary, we're enacting
continuity of government.
A D.C. appellate judge
will meet us at the White House.
Sir, you are now the President
of the United States.
Incredibly alarming live shot.
The United States
Capitol Building in flames.
An explosion... should I say
an unconfirmed explosion...
Going off just moments ago
during President
Richmond's State of the Union address.
Of course, we're reaching out
to all of our sources...
Pick up. Come on.
Hi. This is Scott. I'm
not available right now.
Please leave me a message
after the beep.
Hey, it's me.
Call me when you get this.
I need to know you're okay.
Hey, Scott?
No, it's Doug. I
need you here right away.
Yes, sir. I'm on my way.
Ma'am...
We got to get our kids here.
We've already sent agents
to bring them here.
We are still working to
get all the information
of exactly what happened...
Sir, please.
Ma'am, please hold the Bible.
Just hold the Bible. Thank you.
Sir, place your left hand on
the Bible and repeat after me.
"I, Thomas Adam Kirkman,
do solemnly swear..."
I, Thomas Adam Kirkman,
do solemnly swear...
"...that I will faithfully
execute the office
of President of the United States..."
...that I will faithfully
execute the office
of President of the United States...
"...and will, to
the best of my ability..."
...and will, to the
best of my ability...
"...preserve, protect, and defend
the Constitution of the United States."
...preserve, protect, and defend
the Constitution of the United States,
so help me God.
Mr. President.
Ma'am.
Mr. President, you're gonna
have to come with me now.
Mrs. Kirkman, the Secret Service
will take you up to the residence now.
- Ma'am, please come with me.
- Mr. President.
- Right now.
- Please.
Aaron, where are we going?
The Presidential Emergency
Operations Center.
...every team we have worldwide.
I want every drone waiting on full staff
- and deployable as soon as
they get the order. - Excuse me.
Can you do that?
Well, get it done.
Excuse me.
Hey, hey! Hey!
I need you all to be quiet right now.
Please.
Let's take a moment
for our fallen friends,
heroes one and all.
Thank you.
Maybe we should go around the table.
Where's the CIA director?
We're still working to
set up a secure comm.
The hell with secure comms.
We have to get him patched in now...
Cellphone, landline, Skype...
Whatever we got.
Who's got the networks?
Okay, you tell them
we'll be live in 60 minutes
from the East Room, okay?
Nobody talks to any press
of any office or agency
under threat of me ripping
your insides out.
Do we know who's responsible for this?
Still too early to determine.
We got to give them something, Karen.
The whole world is watching
us right now.
Exactly. We need to alert
every one of our embassies
to convey to each host nation
that the U.S. is on a war footing
and now is not the time to test us.
Patch me into 24-hour
watch at the Pentagon.
Inform the surviving joint
chiefs we are going to DEFCON 2.
You can't make that call.
The Chairman of the
Joint Chiefs is gone.
That doesn't give you
any authority, Harris.
We're under attack. What more
authority do you want?
Who do you think you are?
I want the Air Force
flying in 15 minutes.
Who are you to give me orders?
Who are you to question them, Peter?
I'm not gonna sit on my ass
and hope for the best here.
Let it all out, man.
We're all feeling the same way tonight.
Sorry. I thought I was alone.
Yeah, well, nothing
is what it seems anymore.
You know, an hour ago, I
was throwing back tequila,
celebrating the three lines I
got into a 10,000-word speech.
Swear to God, I don't know how the hell
we're gonna get through this.
Same way we always do.
Yeah, right.
Do you even know who's
in charge right now?
I'm asking, because I
can't even remember his name.
Kirkman. Tom Kirkman.
Oh, yeah, yeah. Kirkland. That's right.
The lowest rung on the ladder.
Did you know President Richmond
fired him this morning?
Now he's the President.
He's the one the country's
gonna be turning to
in our darkest hour.
Well, maybe he'll surprise you.
Yeah, you mean maybe he'll realize
he has no business running the country?
That he should just step aside,
maybe let one of the generals
take over or the CIA director,
somebody who actually knows
what the hell they're doing?
Fat chance of that happening.
Nobody around here ever gives up power.
Kirkland's a follower.
We need a leader.
I'm telling you, man, I got half
a mind to make a run to Canada.
You know what I'm saying?
Oh.
Canada.
Uh, Mr. President.
Do you really believe everything
you just said?
Uh, Mr. President, let me explain.
What's your name?
Seth Wright.
Seth Wright. You're a speechwriter.
I saw you coming out of
Charlie's office earlier this morning.
You were arguing about
the President's address.
Uh, the AB-33 section.
Housing reform.
You really think I should step down?
I do.
You may be right.
But for now, I'm all you got,
and you have...
exactly 52 minutes to write a speech
convincing the American people
that that's a good thing.
Penny!
Mommy!
All right, listen up.
No one comes in or out without tin.
I want a secure
perimeter, at least five blocks out.
I want TSA screening equipment
installed now.
- Got it?
- Yes, sir.
All right, back to work.
You'll also want to send up
thermo UAVs and air sniffers
to look for anything biological
or radiological in the area.
Hannah, you were supposed
to report to HQ.
I was 10 blocks away.
Any survivors?
No, not yet.
EMS is digging through the rubble.
Make sure that Haz-Mat knows...
Agent Wells, you're SIOC,
okay, you're not a field agent.
I need you heading up a crisis
team at the operations center.
Don't need me behind a computer.
You need me here.
- I worked both bomb sites...
- Hannah...
...on the ground in Brussels and Paris.
I know what to look for.
Jason... please, I need to be here.
Nolan. Lawrence.
Yes, Deputy Director?
You're with Wells.
Anyone claiming responsibility?
No, not yet.
All right, Eric, I want
the license plates
of every car parked in
the next three blocks scanned.
If any of them are stolen or
owned by anyone on a watch list,
you tear that car apart.
Mark, bomb disposal techs, CSI,
we catalog what we find
and where we found it.
Let's move.
Thomas Adam Kirkman was
born December 29th, 1967,
in Port Washington, New York.
Before being appointed
Secretary of Housing
and Urban Development,
Kirkman worked in academia
as an educator...
This is insane.
Guy's never been elected to anything.
He ran HUD. They find
affordable homes for people,
which makes Kirkman a glorified
real-estate agent.
He was next in the line of succession.
I'm sorry, but no one
could have foreseen this.
Why the hell do you think
there's a designated survivor, Nikki?
Because this was foreseen.
Now shut up and let me work.
Hey.
What are you doing out here?
I just needed a minute.
How's Penny?
Ah, God.
Scared. Confused.
You know, I mean, just
like everyone, I guess.
Is this even happening?
What the hell am I doing here, Alex?
I'm not the guy for this.
You want to quit?
I know it's not the right thing to say,
but I can't help but feel...
Like running for our lives.
Yeah.
Tom, maybe we should.
Look what happened tonight.
How many people... We
haven't even processed.
And our kids?
Are we putting them in danger?
I mean...
We're a target now.
Are they?
I-I-I don't know...
- Mr. President.
- Yeah?
You said Leo was at a
friend's house tonight.
Yeah, Caleb West.
I just spoke to our agents
at his residence
and Leo wasn't there.
He never was.
What?
Where is he?
We don't know.
They're gonna find Leo.
Mike knows him.
Secret Service... They're
the best in the world at this.
I know.
Mr. President. This way, please.
Please give me a sec.
I got this.
After you.
This is Major Cameron.
Mr. President, this is
the nuclear football.
It'll be with you
whenever you leave the White House.
These are the launch codes,
verification codes,
a listing of every classified location
capable of launching nuclear weapons.
In the event of an imminent strike,
you can green-light
it using this phone.
It works anywhere on Earth
as well as beneath it.
Do you need my fingerprints
or an eye scan or something?
No, sir. It's not like the movies.
It doesn't work that way.
Of course.
Mr. President, the UN
is in emergency session.
I have a three-page phone list
with every one of our enemies
calling to deny responsibility
for the attack.
All US military bases are on full alert,
and the USS Eisenhower
is currently hard charging
towards the Fifth Fleet
stationed in the Persian Gulf.
I understand alerting our bases,
but why are we "hard charging"
a US aircraft carrier anywhere?
Mr. President, in
the event of an attack...
An attack from who?
Y-You just said all our enemies
are denying responsibility.
Because all warfare
is based on deception
and there are still plenty
we haven't heard from.
I just don't feel comfortable
showing that kind of force yet.
With all due respect, sir,
would you mind telling us
when you do plan on being comfortable?
You'll be the first to know, General.
Excuse me.
Pleasure doing business with you.
So, how many more bags you got?
I just sold my last two.
Still got three left.
Save 'em. We got to bounce anyway.
Screw that.
I came here to make money
and have some fun.
- Leo!
- Get off me, man!
Mike?
What are you doing here?
How'd you find me?
It wasn't easy.
We had to open up an ops center at NSA,
run the phone records
of all your friends
and classmates through PRISM
till we could piece together
enough chatter keywords
to trace your digital
footprint to the club.
Really?
No, Leo.
We pinged your phone.
You're not exactly
a criminal mastermind.
I thought you were taking me home.
I am.
Everyone is at a
complete loss for words.
This is the most devastating
attack on our country since 9/11.
And staffers at the White House
are asking the same question
as the rest of the country.
Who's behind this
horrific act of terror?
Look, can you please just check again?
My name is Emily Rhodes.
I am Secretary Kirkman's Chief of Staff.
He was the designated survivor tonight.
Look, I already told you
you're not on the cleared list.
I was just in there this morning.
Well, a lot's happened since then,
in case you haven't noticed.
Step back from the gate.
Intelligence sources
are being tight-lipped
about what has happened
at the Capitol today,
but as of yet, no one has
claimed responsibility
and our nation remains on high alert.
Thank you for your prayers,
Madam Prime Minister.
You, too.
Goodbye.
Right, where were we?
Uh, the presidential voice.
Which, apparently, I don't have.
You can defend my honor at any time.
I will... when he says
something I disagree with.
Okay, so, what do you think
the presidential voice is?
Uh, "All of us here know
there is work to be done.
We have a responsibility
to light the way for every American."
Sounds good to me.
I imagine it would.
You said it two years ago
in Atlanta at the Conference
for the New Urbanism.
Sir, tonight, you're
speaking to the world.
America doesn't need
another friend right now.
You can't be relaxed or disarming.
That's gonna work anymore.
Mr. President, you need to be
stronger than you've ever been before.
We all need that right now.
What is it, Tom?
I've got to go.
Just sit down.
It's okay. We're all feeling it.
Thank you, ma'am.
Alex, please.
Uh, no, ma'am.
You're the First Lady.
Hey.
No, no. Please, sit down.
Sat imagery shows 10
Iranian Navy destroyers
leaving Bandar Abbas port
and taking up positions along
the Strait of Hormuz.
The Strait of Hormuz is where
30% of the world's oil passes through.
I know what it is, Aaron.
Mr. President, this is
a purposeful provocation
by the Iranians to take
advantage of the night's events
and choke off the Western
world's main supply of oil.
Just as we're on our knees,
they're gonna step on our throat.
Aaron.
I finally got past
the gate. What's going on?
I can't talk right now, Emily.
I need to get back to the PEOC.
- Is Tom gonna be in there?
- Well, it is his meeting.
Well, then I'm coming with you.
Sorry, Emily, but in there,
it's code-word clearance only.
I've been with Secretary
Kirkman's staff for three years.
It's President Kirkman now,
and you're not authorized.
If you are choosing this moment
for a pissing contest, Aaron...
That's my point, Emily.
This is no contest.
Now, if you'll excuse me...
President Kirkman needs
people he knows by his side.
You and I have our differences.
I know. And you don't want me in there.
But you also know
better than anyone else
why it is important that I
am there for him right now.
How many more ways can I say this?
In the morning, our economy
is going to go over a cliff,
and the Iranians are just
seizing the moment.
What do you want me to do, General?
Declare war?
Why not?
40 minutes ago, they
showed me the nuclear football.
I guess I've had it
long enough to try it out.
We've just been attacked.
The world thinks it can
test us right now,
and a full, swift show of force
is the only way to remind them
that our flag is still
flying strong tonight.
And all I'm saying is that I think
there are different ways to show force.
What you need to understand
is the Iranians respect
only one course of action,
and that is action.
This is not some consumer group
waiting for a photo
op with a figurehead.
Figurehead.
Well, General,
this figurehead paid attention
during the Cabinet meetings,
where we dealt with this very issue.
And the Iranians have tried to
close off the Strait of Hormuz
for the last 35 years,
so I am having a difficult
time believing
that they just up and decided
to do that tonight.
And how can you be so certain of that?
When is the Iranian ambassador
due to arrive?
15 minutes.
Okay, General.
You can scramble your bombers,
but they are not to engage.
We are going to do this my way.
If it doesn't work, we'll try yours.
I know you're scared, peanut,
but everything's gonna be okay.
But why are we here?
'Cause this, uh... this
is gonna be our new home.
But why?
Because some bad people
did something bad tonight,
and it's Dad's job to make
sure we're all safe.
Are you scared?
Yeah.
Is Daddy?
Are you kidding?
Dad's not scared of anything.
Hi. This is Scott.
I'm not available right now.
Please leave me a message
after the beep.
It's me again.
Where are you?
Please call me back and...
And tell me you're okay.
I love you.
Agent Wells. I was looking for you.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Did you lose someone?
I think we all lost someone.
What do you got?
I-I checked all the license
plates in the area
against every watch list.
Nothing so far.
All right, get in touch with the NSA.
Make sure that they know...
We got something over here!
- What do we got?
- UXO! We got a UXO!
Clear the perimeter!
All right. Clear the area!
We've got a bomb!
Back up now!
Clear the area now!
Perimeter is secure.
You may proceed.
Copy that.
All clear. Open it up.
Okay. Removing the outer case.
Hemostat.
What do you see?
Wires to the fuze compartment,
to the creep spring,
to the detonator.
But no pressure plate.
Easy.
It's clear.
Bomb's a dud.
Is he here?
Yes, he's... he's waiting just outside.
Send him in.
Mr. Ambassador.
Mr. President.
Please.
Thank you.
Please, allow me to begin
by extending to you
and the American people
my country's most sincere sympathies
on this horrific tragedy.
If there is anything our people can do
in response to this
tremendous act of cowardice,
rest assured, we will do it.
I appreciate that.
You can begin by
removing your destroyers
from the Strait of Hormuz.
Mr. President, excuse me,
but I believe you have been misinformed.
Is that a fact?
Yes. We... We have moved
no such destroyers into
the Strait of Hormuz.
My defense department
has war-gamed this out.
They're waiting for me to
give them the green light,
which, I assure you, I will do
unless you pull your destroyers
back to Bandar Abbas
within the next three hours.
Mr. President, I would...
Mr. Ambassador, you
may not know much about me,
but what you should know
is that I'm about as straight a shooter
as you're gonna find in Washington.
So you should believe me when
I tell you that I do not want,
as my first act as Commander
in Chief, to attack Iran.
But as both of us know,
it's not always up to us
how history plays itself out.
Now, I have chosen to believe
that your country is not playing
on our emotions tonight,
but nevertheless, you will
feel the full impact of them
if you do not comply with my demands.
Mr. Ambassador, dock your destroyers
or the lead story on the morning news
will not be about
the attack on our capital
but the devastating attack on yours.
Please, Mr. Ambassador,
let's not get off on
the wrong foot here tonight.
Mr. President, I will speak
with my government.
Thank you, Mr. Ambassador.
Mr. Ambassador, this way.
Mr. Ambassador.
Three hours.
Haven't seen one of those before.
It's a Soviet-era anti-tank mine.
There are still
thousands of them in Afghanistan.
Jihadist terror groups
have been using them for years
as their primary IEDs.
Hannah, you hearing this?
Agent Wells, the bomb is...
Is an unexploded
munition you think was used
by a Mideast terror group...
Either ISIS, Al-Qaeda, or the Taliban...
To blow up our Capitol.
Yes, I heard you.
And that's one theory.
You got another one?
All right.
In the weeks
leading up to the big ones...
9/11, Paris, Belgium...
The chatter we were getting
was off the charts.
Something was coming, you know?
We just didn't know what it was.
Do you know what I'm hearing now?
Nothing.
No breaks in any of the routines
of the mosques or camps we're inside,
no one is relocated
their wives or children
in anticipation of our counterattacks.
It's business as usual.
That makes no sense.
So, you're saying the bomb
isn't one of theirs.
I'm saying that if they did this,
they'd be crowing right now.
There is a reason
the people who did this
are keeping silent about it.
And that is?
You don't take credit for something
until you're done, right?
So, what if they're
just getting started?
I don't remember this suit.
I had to borrow it.
You look the part.
I know this is gonna
change everything for us,
but I have to do it.
If I don't...
I just have to.
You still on my side?
I'm always on your side...
Mr. President.
Something needs to be done, Aaron.
I think we're doing
everything that's expected of us, Harris.
That's not what I'm talking about.
What exactly are you talking about here?
Because if it's what I think it is,
this conversation's going to
be treading dangerously close
to conspiracy to commit treason.
We have a Housing and Urban
Development Secretary
running the free world.
You call it treason.
I call it my civic responsibility.
You're talking about
removing a sitting president.
An unelected president, yes.
Listen to me.
If the country's gonna survive,
we need to act swiftly and definitively.
Tom Kirkman will not
get us through this.
And let me guess... You can?
We're in a state of war.
Who would you rather have leading us?
Uh, Mr. President.
Your glasses.
They're not very presidential, sir.
Right.
Thank you.
Mr. President, you're live
in five, four, three...
My fellow Americans...
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --