Previously on "Designated Survivor"...
Capitol's been attacked. Eagle is gone.
- Congress, the Cabinet.
- Oh, oh.
Sir, you are now the President.
Some bad people did
something bad tonight,
and it's Dad's job to make
sure we're all safe.
I've been with Secretary
Kirkman's staff for three years.
It's President Kirkman now,
and you're not authorized.
Do we know who's responsible for this?
Still too early to determine.
We got to give them something,
the whole world is watching.
We have a Housing and Urban
Development Secretary
running the free world.
You're talking about
removing a sitting president.
Man: We got something over here!
Easy.
What do you see?
It's clear. Bomb's a dud.
You don't take credit for something
until you're done, right?
So, what if they're
just getting started?
Hannah: There was no chatter.
Jason: Hannah, I
understand there was no chatter,
but we still need to check
all of the usual suspects...
Al Qaeda, Hezbollah, Al-Sakar.
Where are we with local law enforcement?
I've coordinated with D.C. police,
Secret Service, Metro, and Capitol.
All right, that's good. Now,
remember... The high-value target list
only starts with the White House.
We need to heighten security
at every location.
Already taken care of.
Man: Hey! Let's get on this bomb!
- You taking that bomb to Andrews?
- Yeah.
Top brass wants everything
cataloged under one roof.
Man: Deputy Director!
We need you over here!
All right.
Man: All right, pull that out!
Tom: My fellow Americans,
tonight our way of life
came under attack.
This act of cowardice was meant
to cripple our nation.
But as before,
America will show the world
that we will not bow down to fear,
that we will fight back,
that we will persevere.
Male reporter: And this was
President Tom Kirkman's
first address to the nation.
It came just two hours
after he was unceremoniously
sworn in as our new president.
Unfortunately, last night's speech
did little to calm the frayed nerves...
Woman №1: Words aside,
Kirkman is an
unelected, untested HUD secretary
at a time where the world
is looking for leadership.
Woman №2: ...remains of the Capitol,
searching for both survivors
and answers to the questions
all Americans are asking...
How did this happen
and will life ever be the sa...
- Man: Morning, Mr. President.
- Good morning.
Tom: West Wing, right or left?
This way, to the right, sir.
Thank you very much.
Phoenix on the move.
Man: Good morning, sir.
My wife didn't want me to come in today.
She's afraid the White House is next.
Woman: I was supposed to go last night,
but I couldn't get a sitter.
What are we gonna do?
Melissa's dead, everyone's dead.
Aaron: Mr. President.
- Aaron.
- Good morning.
We have a briefing
- waiting for you in the Oval, sir.
- Good.
- Mr. President.
- Wyatt, right?
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you.
Aaron: Sir, I just have to warn you.
This might be a bit more hectic
than you're used to.
I-I understand. I think we'll be fine.
We've added increased
security to our oil and gas pipelines,
power grids,
refineries, chemical storage tanks.
Mass transit is still on lock down...
Planes and trains.
Immigration remains frozen.
Sir, you have to authorize
- we close the banks immediately.
- No, we can't do that.
We cannot keep the
American people from their money.
48 hours without Bank of America
is better than a 48-month depression.
If everyone withdraws
their money at the same time,
the banks will collapse.
Where are we at with the bombing?
Cochrane: Deputy Director Atwood
will be briefing us soon,
but we're looking at groups
with the skills and resources
to do something like this.
Hezbollah, Al-Qaeda, North Korea, RGB.
Well, what's this about
violence in Michigan?
We're getting reports
of flare-ups in Dearborn.
Police targeting the local
Muslim community.
Yeah, but what I want to know is
how did the terrorists bring explosives
into the Capitol Building
in the first place.
We're working on that.
In the meantime, we have to
go after everyone we suspect.
We go after them, after their families
- any way we can.
- Emily: I'm sorry.
Are you talking about
enhanced interrogation?
They destroyed our Capitol.
I'm saying we do whatever we have to do.
Man: Can I just get a moment?!
Everybody, why don't we just
focus on one thing at a time?
Please, excuse me.
Please, can you just give me a moment?
_
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --
Tom... I'm sorry.
Mr. President.
I just needed to find somewhere quiet.
Aaron: Yeah, admittedly,
it got a little loud in there.
Loud?
A Caps game is loud, Aaron.
Back there in the Oval
Office, that was chaos.
We need order, a system,
or this is never gonna work.
We need to get this government
up and running.
W... We need a cabinet and fast.
That's a good idea, sir,
but first order of business
is going to be naming
your Chief of Staff.
Seriously? You're making
a play right now?
Enough!
I'm not ready to make that decision.
What I need is both of you to step up
and help me put together a cabinet.
Tell me you can do that.
- Yes, Mr. President.
- Of course.
Good.
For now, we're gonna close the banks.
ATMs and credit will still be available.
I want you to monitor
the situation in Michigan,
and I want you to keep me up to speed
on the investigation into the bombing.
The American people
want to know who did this,
- and so do I.
- Sir.
Also...
Later today, I want to see
the Capitol Building,
or what's left of it.
Are you sure that's a...
- good idea right now, sir?
- No, no, no.
Th... that... that's exactly
what you need, sir.
A do-over.
L-Last night's speech
didn't exactly put minds at ease.
But you, sir, at the site...
Now that sends a message.
- It shows a...
- Respect, Aaron.
It shows respect.
It's not a photo-op.
- Whatever you say, sir.
- Good.
Let's get back to work.
Sir. Hold it right there.
Morning, what's going on?
- What's in the backpack?
- What?
Your backpack... What's in it?
Uh, just my stuff for, uh, work...
- Papers and stuff.
- Cop №2: Where do you work?
I work at the White House.
Really? The White House?
Yeah, you know,
where the President sleeps.
You being a wise ass?
I'd like to know why you stopped me.
Why don't you tell us where you
live and show us some I.D. first.
I live right there.
It's cold and it's cramped,
but I can walk to my gym,
so I got that going for me.
Cop №1: Seth Wright.
Is that your real name?
According to my mother.
Cop №2: Keith.
This looks good.
Thanks for your cooperation, Mr. Wright.
Thank you.
Yeah, stay safe.
Look, I got to go.
Tell Mom I love her.
Okay, cabinet members.
What about Blanchard?
For State?
He's qualified... Three years as deputy.
He also has two secret Facebook accounts
and an affinity for the coeds
who look after his kids.
I'm thinking Garfield's our guy.
No, think again.
He's made more than a few
enemies on the Hill.
Emily, I hate to break it to you,
but there is no Hill anymore.
Oh, my God.
There's no Hill anymore.
Something happened in Michigan.
What?
- Mr. President.
- You don't need to get up
every time I walk into a room.
I'm not the Queen.
No, sir. Virtually no resemblance.
I'm sorry to interrupt.
I... I actually came in to apologize.
Apologize?
Last night, you wrote me
a home run of a speech.
This morning, it seems like the press
wished anybody else delivered it but me.
Mr. President.
Maybe the country's just not ready, yet,
to come together behind anyone,
even with the best speech in the world.
Maybe.
Aaron: Mr. President.
There's something you need to see.
Woman: Police imposing a curfew
on predominantly Muslim neighborhoods
and ordering residents
to obey it or face arrest.
These are citizens
who have not been charged
with any crimes,
who are simply targeted
because of their religious beliefs.
The American Civil Liberties Union
denounced the actions by Dearborn police
- as a violation of an individual's...
- Mr. President, we're ready.
...basic civil rights.
But in the wake of
the attack on the Capitol,
some are saying this is
just the type of policing
this country needs.
- Governor...?
- Royce.
Governor Royce, how are you?
Uh, about as expected.
There's a lot to manage
here, as you can imagine.
I know, and I want to help.
I've seen reports that
the police in Dearborn
are rounding up members
of the Muslim community.
- Woman: Thank you, sir.
- Yes, I'm aware.
Well, like I said, we'd
like to help you stop the police.
Why would I stop the police?
They're acting on my orders.
- Your orders?
- That's correct.
I don't know if you know this,
but I have the largest Muslim population
in the country, here.
That doesn't mean they're doing
anything wrong or that they've been radicalized.
No, but I'm willing to bet
they know someone who is.
Governor, you can't target
an innocent population
because you're scared.
- You have a responsibility...
- To all my citizens.
And my first and only priority
is to make sure they're safe,
something that Washington...
If... if there even is
such a place anymore...
Has proven incapable of doing.
Governor, the federal government...
...was effectively
snuffed out last night.
There is no Congress,
there is no Supreme Court.
When it comes to the people of Michigan,
I am the highest authority,
and you have none over me.
With all due respect, sir,
I am the President.
Not mine.
So you'll have to excuse
me, Mr. Kirkman.
While you're busy
learning how to become President,
I've got 10 million citizens to protect.
Governor?
Governor Royce? Hello?
Sir, you should know
that messages of support
continue to pour in
from heads of state around the world.
We should go over
which calls you want
to return personally.
I would think all of them.
How many calls are we talking about?
About 175, sir.
Maybe we should prioritize.
Mr. President.
I want you to know that I don't care
what the so-called pundits are saying.
I was very moved by your
words last night.
Well, thank you.
Excuse me, but who are you?
Mr. President, this is congresswoman
- Kimble Hookstraten.
- Congresswoman.
Yes, I was last night's
other designated survivor.
Other designated...
Excuse us, please.
Thank you, sir.
There are two designated survivors?
Yeah, the Republicans chose someone
to sit out of the
State of the Union, as well.
So they'd be represented.
Smart.
Hey, what do you know about Hookstraten?
Um, you were on Senator Carlyle's staff
when they were both on
Ways and Means, weren't you?
- Stalker.
- Come on.
She's smart. Very smart.
Third-generation D.C. blue
blood, nine years, Republican whip,
knows every detail about
every player in town.
So you're saying she's
a lot more experienced
than the President?
Come on. Let's go get
Governor Royce on the phone.
435 representatives, 100 senators,
and 9 justices.
And now it's just down to the two of us.
I know.
You don't know
whether to feel... ashamed
or grateful to be alive.
Apologetic.
Sir?
To the American people
for being stuck with me as their leader.
I mean, let's face it.
The pundits might be right.
Mr. President.
Do you know what I did
this morning, sir?
I cried and then I prayed.
Do you know when the last time
I did those two things together was?
9/11?
Nobody thought we could
get through it back then,
but we did.
And nobody thinks we
can get through it now,
but we will.
This is your house now.
So make it your own.
Whatever you need, just ask.
Republican, Democrat, Independent...
It doesn't matter anymore.
We're all Americans today.
Thank you, Congresswoman.
Kimble, please.
Okay.
Kimble, later this afternoon,
I'm going to the Capitol site
to thank the first responders.
I think it would be a nice show of unity
if we were to do that together.
What do you say?
I'd be honored, sir.
Thank you, Mr. President.
Thank you.
Ronnie, is that the unexploded munition?
Yep.
Hannah: What's it telling us?
Russian anti-tank mine,
likely pulled from
the ground in Afghanistan.
But look here.
The guts are cannibalized.
Cyrillic on the outside,
but the lock ring is Pakistani,
and the firing pin is newer,
probably Iranian.
Well, that is
consistent with what we've seen
from some Jihadist terror groups.
Well, we should be able
to point the finger directly
when we get the lab results
from the other bombs.
Right, but this one,
why didn't this one go off?
Any number of reasons.
Russian red wire to Iranian
green doesn't work,
the main charge degraded.
But I wouldn't rule out
good old-fashioned human error.
You're telling me that the people
who blew up our
U.S. Capitol in one shot,
didn't test the triggers, the wiring?
Then what are you suggesting?
Hannah?
What if this bomb wasn't
meant to explode?
What if it was meant to be found?
Look, I don't care what
the Governor's doing.
The President of the United Sates
needs to talk to him.
No, I'm not... I'm not asking you.
I'm telling you.
I'm not... I'm not gonna hold.
Damn it!
You'd think there would be more people
qualified for Attorney General.
Seth: What the hell
am I supposed to say?
Is this a writer thing?
I'm trying to find a way to unite us
at Kirkman's remarks at the rubble,
but Michigan is probably
just the beginning.
The world is falling apart.
Probably don't want to
put that in the speech.
Aaron: Yes, I'm still here.
God, it's unbelievable.
I like Wynbrandt.
He went to city college at night,
law school, good family man.
Massey's our guy.
He clerked for Thomas, he went to Yale,
editor of the Law Journal.
It's all about what's on paper for you.
I heard Wynbrandt speak.
The man has good values.
Emily, the Governor of Michigan
is basically declaring
his state a sovereign nation,
so we don't have time for values.
I probably shouldn't put that
in the speech either, right?
Alex: Governor Royce said that?
That he's the highest authority?
That's what he said...
And in no uncertain terms.
Then he hung the phone up on me.
Well, he doesn't get to do that.
He has a constitutional obligation...
Don't you get it, Alex?
Royce wants to tear up the Constitution,
and he's not the only one.
Well, you can't let him.
Trust me, I'm not going to.
We've got some lawyers coming over
from the Attorney General's office.
We'll figure out what
our legal options are,
and we're handle it.
How you holding up?
I spoke to Duncan.
The courts are closed.
Markets, banks, schools,
airports, everything.
Half the junior associates in the firm,
they're thinking of leaving Washington.
How's Penny?
You think she even understands
what's happening?
Besides the fact that
we now live in the White House,
her father is the President,
and she's sleeping in a very big bed,
no, not really.
I've been trying to
keep her away from the TV.
And Leo?
He's been in his room
all day, with the door shut.
So, basically being Leo.
Basically.
Do you think we could, for five minutes,
just pretend that this
isn't really happening?
Kind of hard to do in the Oval Office.
Wyatt: I'm sorry, sir.
I told him you were busy.
It's all right.
How can I help you, General?
I'm afraid that's something
we have to discuss in
private, Mr. President.
Oh. This is my wife.
Your wife does not have
code-word clearance, sir.
Alex: Of course.
I'll go.
Ma'am.
What is it?
I just spoke to FBI
Deputy Director Atwood.
The lab results came in.
They've made a
positive I.D. on the explosives.
We know who blew up the Capitol.
Al-Sakar likes
mass-causality attacks...
A chlorine storage tank in Manila,
sarin gas tanks lobbed onto
our military base in Nairobi.
Preliminary analysis
from the FBI's Explosive Device Center
tells us that residue
found on the Capitol debris
is consistent with bombs
used by Al-Sakar in the past.
Mr. President,
it's time to publicly name Al-Sakar
as the perpetrator of this crime
- and take appropriate action.
- Tom: Okay.
Before we do anything,
the FBI is absolutely certain
that Al-Sakar was behind the attack?
75%, sir.
75%?
That's as high as it gets when
it comes to a call like this.
75% is still a "C" on a test, General.
This is not a test. This is war.
All the more reason to
get it right, don't you think?
Sir, I know we got off
on the wrong foot.
You did a fine job staving
off the Iranians last night.
But I am advising you
that the country is on the brink,
and talk will not work here.
America is demanding action
and I am giving you
an enemy we can kill.
You think I don't want to strike back
against the people who did this?
I lost colleagues, friends,
people I love.
I want to find every single person
involved in this attack
from planning to execution
and rip them limb from limb,
which is why I need to know
exactly who did this.
Come back to me with more than 75%,
and I'll launch the
damn missiles myself.
How much more.
25%, damn it!
The death toll as of 30
minutes ago is 900 plus.
That includes the
President, Vice President, Cabinet,
those we've been able to I.D.
from Congress and the Supreme Court...
and FBI Director Jacobs
is also confirmed dead.
The working theory is,
this is the work of Al-Sakar.
So as we know, this is the
latest offshoot of Al-Qaeda.
They are dispersed
throughout North Africa,
which makes them
very, very hard to track.
So we need to be crafty.
We need to reach out to your sources,
spread some cash around,
do whatever you have to
do to firm up that link.
Hannah: What about credit?
What about it?
Is Al-Sakar taking credit?
No, they haven't.
But it was months before Bin Laden
took responsibility
for the Towers, so...
That's all for now.
Agent Wells.
How are you doing?
Same as everyone else, I guess.
I just came from Andrews.
The bomb we just found, the UXO,
it may not be telling you
what you think it is.
Okay, I'll bite.
All right, well, what if
they wanted us to find it
so that we would look at Al-Sakar
and not consider any other options.
Can you back up your theory?
Well, my theories
were good enough for you
in '09 in Iraq.
This is different,
Hannah, and you know it.
Besides, I've already
talked to General Cochrane
and the Joint Chiefs.
But you're still gonna
brief the President later, right?
Best to give them all the
theories, don't you think?
So if it wasn't Al-Sakar,
who blew up the Capitol Building?
I don't know, yet, and
that's what scares me.
Thanks, Mike.
Okay, w-what do I do?
Am I supposed to smile
because I'll probably feel like crying.
- Just be yourself.
- I know, I just...
I don't want to let you down.
I don't want to let the country down,
and I hate this that
they picked it out for me.
Look. I look like the White House sofa.
It's to fit over this, ma'am.
Mike, is this all really necessary?
Two ways the President and his family
can leave the White House...
Out the front door in Kevlar vests
and a 13-car armored motorcade
or out the back in a
Chevy and a ball cap.
Give me the coat.
Penny: Daddy!
Hey, little pea, how are you?
What are you wearing?
Oh, this?
This is just to
protect me in case I fall down.
Cool thing is you can punch
it, and I won't feel a thing.
Go on, try.
Come here.
I love you so much.
- It's time, sir.
- Okay.
H-H-Hold on. W-Where's Leo?
Relax, Mom, I'm here.
Okay, you need to watch your sister.
And keep her away from the TV, okay?
Any of the news, it's too real.
She doesn't need to see it.
Have you got that?
Yeah, I understand.
Aaron: Sir, you won't be wearing a tie.
It's not a formal occasion, Aaron.
Okay. Let's go.
Mike: Phoenix is ready and on the move.
Mike, just out of curiosity,
what was it before?
Sir?
My code name when I
was Secretary of HUD,
what was it?
"Glasses," sir.
We left word for the Governor
three hours ago.
Yeah, p-please tell him, again.
Forget politics, it's just plain rude.
I mean, what the hell's
wrong with people anyway?
People are scared, Aaron.
The Capitol used to be
a symbol of strength,
and now it's a pile of ashes.
And everyone we know is gone.
You would think today, of all days,
people could at least
pretend to be decent human beings.
Seth: Why are you so surprised?
Tragedy either makes people
appreciate their fellow men,
or fear them.
The Governor's no different.
He's just elected.
Thanks for coming with me.
Alex: Of course.
What?
Yesterday, I was asked to resign,
and we were talking about
moving to Montreal.
Now I'm trying to put
the entire U.S. government back together
and stop the country
from tearing itself apart.
Hell of a day.
Yeah.
Man: That's the
President's motorcade coming in.
Look out.
Are you ready for this?
How can anybody be ready for this?
Man: All right, hold the
work. Hold the work.
My God.
Aaron: Sir.
Mr. President.
Tom.
Mr. President,
I'm Jason Atwood, Deputy Director.
We got a briefing
ready for you inside, sir.
Okay.
Atwood: Prelim analysis from TEDAC
indicates that the
explosive residue found on the debris
is called cyclonite, also known as RDX.
We believe it was mixed
with a plasticizer.
And that's what maximizes
the destruction,
allowed the chamber
to come down on itself?
Exactly.
And Al-Sakar has access to RDX?
Yes, sir. It's their signature.
What about the device
you found... the bomb?
Why didn't it go off?
We believe it was human error.
We're still running some tests.
Okay.
Thank you, Deputy Director.
Thank you, Mr. President.
We'll keep you updated.
Mike, take my coat.
Sir, I'm gonna need you
to keep that vest on.
Mike, we're here to project confidence.
Does this vest project
confidence to you?
Thank you.
- I win.
- Leo: You cheated.
- I know your game, little girl.
- I did not.
Oh, I got to take this.
You're supposed to watch me.
It's the White House, Penny.
I'm sure you're safe.
Female Reporter: A truly somber moment,
as newly sworn-in President Kirkman
makes his first visit
to the site of the terrorist attack.
We will stand by for
his comments to the nation.
A lot of cameras, Aaron.
You are the President, sir.
Excuse me. Could I borrow that?
Here you go, sir.
Thank you.
- Just press here?
- Yeah.
Hello, my name is Tom Kirkman.
Last night at approximately 10:30 p.m.,
I was sworn in as
President of the United States.
I've come down here
because I wanted to thank
each and every one of you
for the work that you're doing here
and let you know that America mourns.
This...
This was an act of madness.
This was an act of terror.
Yesterday, we saw the worst in humanity.
Today, I see it's best.
I know you're all tired, scared.
I know you want answers,
someone to blame,
someone to fight against.
I need you to know that
I want that, too.
- Seth: What?
- And even, though, today,
It's Michigan.
...I promise you we will rise again
better and stronger.
Man: Get down!
Those who we've lost...
Are leaders, family members...
...and loved ones.
I swear to you, they
will not have died in vain.
Hey, you see what's
going on in Michigan.
This place where we stand
right here, right now...
Man: Let's get him out of here!
Tom: ...will forever be hallowed ground,
and we must always...
...respect the incredible sacrifice
that was made here.
Reporter: Mr. President,
do you have anything to say
about the Muslim teenager in Dearborn
who was beaten by police?
The President's not
answering any questions right now.
- Thank you.
- You have no response, President Kirkman?
- I-I didn't hear the question.
- The Muslim teenager
who was beaten by police, Mr. President.
- Do you have a comment?
- What?
Are you concerned that their civil
rights are being violated?
Reporter: Is the White House concerned
about escalating violence
against Muslims?
Are you gonna let Americans
get beaten, Mr. Kirkman.
- Man: Show me your hands!
- Sir, I need you to step back.
Don't touch me.
Gun! Gun! Gun!
Mike: Cover and evacuate to the car.
Man: Get your hands off him.
He's not doing anything.
It's a phone. It's a phone!
I have Phoenix! I repeat,
I have Phoenix!
Man: Back up! Back up!
I said back up!
Go, go, go!
Get me Governor Royce on the phone now.
We've been trying.
He won't take the call.
What do you mean he won't take the call?
Do we know anything about
the condition of the boy,
the one in the Michigan?
He's in surgery with internal bleeding.
He knows we're
calling, sir. He doesn't care.
I want to talk to a couple lawyers
from the Attorney General's Office.
- What's his name? How old is he?
- Danny Fayad, ma'am.
We have a couple A.G. candidates
who could be helpful.
Bring them in.
Sorry to bother you, ma'am.
- Your daughter needs you upstairs.
- Okay.
Tom, the boy... he's 17...
The same age as Leo.
Penny needs me. I got to go.
Jason: I don't have to explain
myself to you Hannah.
I gave the President what I determined
was the most relevant intel.
Or you gave him what
the group who did this
wanted you to give him.
How can he lead if he doesn't
have all the facts?
Then you should have given them to me.
Look, it's not...
that I don't belive you,
or that I don't want to.
Someone blew up the Capitol.
Who knows what's possible anymore.
On top of that, we got a guy in office
who's number 11 in
the line of succession.
I can't go to him with
speculation right now.
So, if you want me
to go back to him with your theory,
please prove it.
Tom: The situation in Michigan
is out of control.
Now we've got a teenager
in critical condition.
I need to know what my
legal options are right now.
Well, uh, Mr. President.
You can invoke the Supremacy Clause,
issue an executive order
saying Governor Royce must force
his police to stand down.
Wynbrandt: That's a bad call.
E.O.s can be perceived as very hostile.
Then what would you suggest?
A Presidential Proclamation.
Which is nothing more than
a symbolic empty gesture.
It... it looks weak, sir.
Bush used a Proclamation
to secure disaster areas after Katrina.
That hardly seems like
an empty gesture to me.
I wouldn't take declaring Martial Law
- off the table either, sir.
- If you want this to be
the shortest presidency in history.
Let me get this straight.
An executive order will be
perceived as too hostile,
A Presidential Proclamation... Too weak.
Martial Law...
Either very, very smart
or incredibly self-destructive.
Guys, let me ask you a question.
Can you agree on anything?
- Yes.
- Not really.
Great.
How is she?
Well, how do you think she is?
She just watched her father
almost get trampled.
You had one job...
- to keep her away from the TV.
- I did.
Until you didn't.
Y-You left her alone.
I got a phone call.
It... it's not my job to be her parent.
Well, guess what.
We're all doing jobs
that we weren't doing yesterday.
Leo, nothing's the same anymore.
Look, I know it's asking a lot.
But you're just gonna
have to grow up faster.
I-I'm gonna need to count on you
in more ways than ever.
Can I do that?
Guess we'll find out.
Take these to Treasury.
Tell them Social Security
checks will keep going out,
- if I have to sign them myself.
- Yes, sir.
Aaron, I thought we were in agreement.
Really, General?
About what?
He's in over his head, out of his depth.
You need to convince your new boss
that Al-Sakar is behind the bombing.
I think he was pretty clear in there.
Until he's certain,
he will not name anyone.
And as I recall, it's
your job to convince him.
- Aaron, you're Chief of Staff.
- Actually, I'm not.
- So, who is?
- He hasn't named one, yet.
And yet another trigger he won't pull.
Hi.
Mm. Light reading?
Well, sadly, it seems that Wikipedia
is a little thin on
constitutional-law theory.
Well, did the lawyers
not give you any answers about Michigan.
They gave me plenty of answers.
They just weren't the right ones.
It doesn't even matter, yet.
I can't get Governor Royce
back on the phone.
Well, maybe it's time to force his hand.
What do you mean?
When George Wallace
refused an order to integrate
schools in Alabama,
J.F.K. had his brother
federalize the National Guard
and forced him to obey the law.
"Federalize the National Guard."
Well, it's brilliant,
but it's also a little...
Nuclear.
Yeah.
Hey.
I don't need a nuclear solution.
I need a political one.
Good thing we have a
politician in the family.
We'll see about that.
Man: Mr. President,
your call's on line 1.
Yeah.
Okay, thank you very much.
Alex: Tom?
- The boy from Michigan.
- Danny Fayad.
He just died.
Emily: Mr. President.
- Tell me you got him.
- Yes.
Governor Royce and
Congresswoman Hookstraten
are both on the board
of the American Enterprise Institute.
If anyone can get him
back to the table...
That was smart. Good job.
Okay, Mr. President.
He's coming back on the line now.
- Thank you.
- My pleasure, sir.
Tom: Governor Royce.
You're a hard man to reach.
Well, I told you before.
I'm pretty busy.
Well, we're gonna try
and lighten the load for you,
For the record,
I am ordering you to
have your police stand down
and stop harassing the Muslim
community in Dearborn.
I also need you to release
everybody that you've picked up today
that you have not formally
charged with a crime.
Look, I told you before,
my police are doing what they have to do
to protect my citizens.
With all due respect, Governor,
they're not your citizens.
They're mine, and it's
my job to protect them.
It's a job you have no business doing.
Well, not according to the Constitution.
Governor, you should also know
that your police unknowingly picked up
three undercover operatives
working on a long lead investigation
for Homeland Security.
I can't give you their names
because it's classified,
and you don't have clearance.
That is why I need you to release
everybody that you've picked up today.
Well... I'm not gonna do that.
Well, then, Governor,
you'll be obstructing
a federal investigation.
I'm sure you're aware of
the consequences for that.
Look, I'm just trying
to keep my people safe.
How safe is Danny Fayad this evening?
Governor, I need your answer now.
I'll call the State Police,
tell them to stand down
and release everyone we've picked up.
Thank you.
Aaron: Mr. President,
would you like me to contact
Homeland Security,
tell them their agents
have been released?
There were no agents.
It was a bluff.
A band-aid to stop the
bleeding for now.
Well done, Mr. President.
Governor Royce is a good man.
He was just wrong today.
- Thank you for your help, Kimble.
- Sir.
Thank you, everyone.
Great work.
Seth, can you hold up for a minute?
Walk with me.
D.C. police called the
White House switchboard,
wanted to confirm that you worked here.
What happened this morning?
What happened in Michigan.
What always happens.
When people don't know
who their enemy is,
they start with people who look like me.
They want me to name Al-Sakar
as the group behind the bombing.
But the FBI can't confirm
with absolute certainty
that they did it.
So, I can't do anything.
Otherwise, I'd be just as
bad as Governor Royce.
We got to get this right.
We will, sir.
- How are you getting home?
- Sorry.
How are you getting home?
I can have the Secret Service drive you.
Oh, no. That won't be necessary.
Thank you, Mr. President. I'll be fine.
Be careful, Seth.
Thank you, sir.
Good night.
Wyatt!
Wyatt: Yes, sir.
Could I please have the number
for Danny Fayad's parents?
I need you to know that
words could never express
how sorry I am for your loss.
Yes, sir.
Goodnight.
Hey, Mike.
You wouldn't happen
to have a baseball cap
laying around, would you?
Yes, sir.
You lose someone?
Yeah.
I lost everyone.
Thank you.
Thank you for your service.
Thank you, Mr. President.
Thank you.
Thanks for bringing me here, Mike.
It's an honor, sir.
Man: Hey, over here! We found one!
We got a survivor!
We got a survivor over here!
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --